Register to The David Kraehenbuehl Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Music, Series I
  - Music by David Kraehenbuehl
    - Roman Catholic Service Music, I.I
      - [Hymns arranged or harmonized by David Kraehenbuehl] (Box 6, Folder 95)
        Holy God, we praise Thy name
        Hope for all
        Immaculate Mary
        Jesus, our divine companion
        O God, almighty Father
        O most holy one
        O sacrament most holy
        Now thank we all our God
        Sing of Mary
        Song of the workmen
        Stainless the maiden
        Their message goes forth
        This is my body
        To Jesus Christ, our sovereign King
        What you gave us for our taking
        Word of God to earth descending
        Ye sons and daughters
      - [Organ preludes on J. S. Paluch melodies] (Box 6, Folder 96)
        Carillon: I am the way, 1 p.
        Meditation: Receive in your heart, 4 p.
        Postlude: Go forth, 3 p.
        Prelude: The King of glory, 3 p.
        Recessional: Sing alleluia, 2 p.
        Toccata: Come, Creator spirit, 3 p.
        Variations: He said, 4 p.
      - Mass of the people of God / SATB choir, congregation, organ / David Kraehenbuehl. -- Chicago: J. S. Paluch Co., c.1973., 1 score (11 p.); 28 cm. (Box 6, Folder 97)
      - Mass of the people of God / two-part chorus, congregation in unison, and organ / David Kraehenbuehl. -- Chicago: J. S. Paluch Co., c.1973., 1 score (11 p.); 28 cm. (Box 6, Folder 97)
        Portion of p.11 missing.
      - Mass of the people of God. (Box 6, Folder 97)
        Additional / alternate settings, 6 p.
      - Missa plebs dei: sung Mass of the people of God / by David Kraehenbuehl. -- Chicago: J. S. Paluch Co., c.1967., 1 score (30 p.); 22 x 28 cm. (Box 6, Folder 97)
        For voice and organ.
        On title page: As given in the Monthly Missalette.
      - Service music for the Mass: for unison choir, 2-voice choir, 4-voice choir with organ. -- 4th ed. -- Chicago: J. S. Paluch Co., 1979., 152 p.; 28 cm. (Box 6, Folder 98)
        David Kraehenbuehl listed as a contributing composer.
      - [Service music published in the Seasonal Missalette] (Box 6, Folder 98)
      - [Unattributed settings, some perhaps by David Kraehenbuehl] (Box 6, Folder 99)
        Acclamation set no. 1
        Acclamation set no. 2
        Alleluia
        Call to love
        Celebrate the spirit
        Happy are you
        Heal me
        Holy God
        I have called you by your name
        In the sight of the angels
        Like a child
        Lord, receive your servant
        Rejoice, rejoice, for Jesus Christ is risen
        Seek and you shall find
        Sing praise to God on high
        Song of the suffering servant
        Thank you, Lord
        We praise your name in song
        We thank the Lord
        Your spirit lives in me
    - Sketches, I.J
      - [Sketches] Musical spellings of "Sharolyn Marie Klotz" and "Troy Leif Birdsong.", 1 p.; 28 cm. (Box 6, Folder 100)
  - Music by Other Composers Transcribed or Arranged by David Kraehenbuehl, I.K
    - Pastoral Suite., Chabrier, Emmanuel, 1841-1894; 8 manuscript scores (total 60 p.); 35 cm. (Box 6, Folder 101)
      Arranged for 2 pianos, 8 hands.
      I. Idylle. -- II. Danse Villageoise. -- III. Sous Bois. -- IV. Scherzo- Valse.
    - Eloquence / Joseph Haydn. -- text c.1968 by David Kraehenbuehl., Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809; 1 score (7 p.); 28 cm. (Box 6, Folder 102)
      Photocopy of printed score with manuscript text underlay.
    - Evening prayer / Joseph Haydn. -- text c.1968 by David Kraehenbuehl., Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809; 1 score (10 p.); 28 cm. (Box 6, Folder 102)
    - The ox-cart: from Pictures at an exhibition / Modeste Moussorgsky; arranged for two pianos, eight hands by David Kraehenbuehl. -- Cincinnati: The Willis Music Co., c.1984., Mussorgsky, Modest Petrovich, 1839-1881; 1 score (4 p.) + 2 parts; 31 cm. (Box 6, Folder 103)
      Pl. no.: WMCo. 10616
  - Original Compositions by Other Composers, I.L
    - [Classical compositions in simplified piano arrangements], 12 manuscript scores (15 p. total); 28 cm. (Box 6, Folder 103)
      Manuscript in pencil.
      Arrangements of music by Brahms, Corelli, Dukas, Dvorak, Gluck, Goldmark, Grieg, Ippolitov-Ivanov, Mozart, Offenbach, Rimsky- Korsakoff, and Bizet (sketch)
    - The pianist's Christmas book: a program of settings (solo, duet, ensemble) for Christmas music-making / by Stanley Fletcher. -- Evanston, IL: Summy-Birchard Publishing Co., c.1957., Fletcher, Stanley, 1910-1988; 1 score (23 p.); 28 cm. (Box 6, Folder 104)
      Inscribed on title page: With Christmas greetings to the Kraehenbuehl family from Stanley Fletcher.
    - Troubled night: from "The five-dollar opera" / Stanley Fletcher., Fletcher, Stanley, 1910-1988; 1 manuscript score (11 p.); 28 cm. (Box 6, Folder 104)
      For two pianos, 4-hands.
      At end: 9/86.
    - Twelve psalm-tone intonations: for common, festive and penitential use / by Charles Frischmann. -- Chicago: J. S. Paluch Co., c.1974., Frischmann, Charles; 1 score (5 p.); 28 cm. (Box 6, Folder 105)
      Pub. no.: O-10
    - Sketches for a new scale: for microtunable synthesizer / Christopher U. Light., Light, Christopher U.; 1 score (30 p.); 29 cm. (Box 6, Folder 106)
      1. Scales, Changes and Rounds. -- 2. Fanfare on B.A.C.H. -- 3. Prelude after a prelude by Bach. -- 4. Folk Melody. -- 5. Sketch in 4/4 Time. -- 6. Sketch in 5/8 Time.
    - [Student compositions], 141 p.; various sizes. (Box 7, Folder 107)
      Holographs in pencil, photocopies of holographs.
      Original compositions by young musicians.
- Writings, Series II
  - Writings by David Kraehenbuehl, II.A
    - The affect of Bach / David Kraehenbuehl., 7 p.; 22 cm. (Box 7, Folder 108)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, February 1981, p. 12-18.
    - All things in proportion / by David Kraehenbuehl., 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 108)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Spring 1985, p. 6-8.
    - Another half note on playing ornaments in Bach., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 108)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, Spring 1972, p. 8-9.
      Reprinted in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Autumn 1989, p. 5-6.
    - Another TET offensive / David Kraehenbuehl., 5 p.; 22 cm. (Box 7, Folder 108)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, June 1981, p. 10-14.
    - The art of changing fingers / by David Kraehenbuehl., 6 p.; 22 cm. (Box 7, Folder 108)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, March 1982, p. 3-8.
    - Bach inventions [lecture notes], 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 109)
    - Back to Bach / David Kraehenbuehl., 9 p.; 22 cm. (Box 7, Folder 109)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, January 1981, p. 8-16.
    - Beethoven: lecture III [lecture notes], 1 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 109)
    - Beginning the study of "real music" / by Richard Chronister and David Kraehenbuehl., 4 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 109)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, Winter 1972, p. 11-14.
    - Beginning the study of "real music" (part II) / by Richard Chronister and David Kraehenbuehl., 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 109)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, Spring 1972, p. 19-21.
    - Beginning the study of "real music" (part III) by David Kraehenbuehl and Richard Chronister., 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 109)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, Autumn 1972, p. 3-5.
    - Big music for small hands / by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 109)
      Keyboard Arts Practical Paper.
    - Casting slurs / David Kraehenbuehl., 5 p.; 22 cm. (Box 7, Folder 110)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, September 1980, p. 8-12.
    - Communication: process and purpose / David Kraehenbuehl., 10 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 110)
      Photocopy of typescript.
    - Communication: process and purpose, part I / by David Kraehenbuehl., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 110)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Winter, 1983, p. 6-7.
    - Communication: process and purpose, part II / by David Kraehenbuehl., 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 110)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Spring, 1983, p. 8-10.
    - A composer's use of history [notes], 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 110)
    - A creative approach to fundamentals of music: using the keyboard to teach harmony [lecture notes], 27 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 110)
    - A day with Frances Clark & David Kraehenbuehl [lecture notes] -- Evanston, IL: Summy-Birchard Co., 16 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 111)
    - Deaf, dumb, blind, and lame / David Kraehenbuehl., 9 p.; 22 cm. (Box 7, Folder 111)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, April 1981, p. 12-20.
    - Dealing with performance traps (part I) / by David Kraehenbuehl., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 111)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Winter 1984, p. 5-6.
    - Dealing with performance traps (part III) / by David Kraehenbuehl., 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 111)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Spring 1984, p. 7-9.
    - Don't change that finger! / by David Kraehenbuehl., 6 p; 22 cm. (Box 7, Folder 111)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, February 1982, p. 11-16.
    - Everyone can compose! / David Kraehenbuehl., 9 p.; 22 cm. (Box 7, Folder 112)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, May 1981, p. 2-10.
    - Everyone can compose [lecture notes], 7 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 112)
    - Expression marks [lecture notes], 25 p.; 31 cm. (Box 7, Folder 112)
    - The fingers: source of artistry / David Kraehenbuehl., 4 p.; 22 cm. (Box 7, Folder 112)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, January 1982, p. 8-11.
    - Following the flags / by David Kraehenbuehl., 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 112)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Autumn 1988, p. 6-8.
    - The forearm: source of subtlety / David Kraehenbuehl., 8 p.; 22 cm. (Box 7, Folder 112)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, December 1981, p. 6-13.
    - Forget-me-nots / by David Kraehenbuehl., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 112)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Spring 1988, p. 9-10.
    - Getting out those hard-to-remove spots: part I / by David Kraehenbuehl., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 113)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Autumn 1987, p. 6-7.
    - Getting out those hard-to-remove spots: part II / by David Kraehenbuehl., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 113)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Winter 1988, p. 7-8.
    - Getting the sounds we want (hand and forearm) / by David Kraehenbuehl., 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 113)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, Winter 1975, p. 12-14.
    - Getting the sounds we want (the fingers) / by David Kraehenbuehl., 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 113)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, Autumn 1974, p. 10-12.
    - Getting the sounds we want (upper arm and upper body) / by David Kraehenbuehl., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 113)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, Spring 1975, p. 10-11.
    - Good, better, or best? / by David Kraehenbuehl., 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 113)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, Winter 1974, p. 3-5.
    - A graceful performance: part I / by David Kraehenbuehl., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 113)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, Autumn 1986, p. 3-4.
    - A graceful performance: part II / by David Kraehenbuehl., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 113)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Winter 1987, p. 12-13.
    - Guidelines for teachers [notes], 27 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 113)
    - A half note on the playing of ornaments., 1 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 114)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, Winter 1972, p. 4.
      Reprinted in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Autumn 1989, p. 4-5.
    - Hannon is not the answer / by David Kraehenbuehl., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 114)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, Autumn 1975, p. 4-5.
    - Here we go again! / by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 114)
      Published in Keyboard Arts: A Journal for Keyboard Teachers, Autumn 1977, p. 5.
      Reprinted in Keyboard Arts, Summer 1982, p. 4.
    - Information as a measure of structure in music / Edgar Coons and David Kraehenbuehl., 35 p.; 23 cm. (Box 7, Folder 115)
      Reprinted from the Journal of Music Theory, v. 2, no. 2 (November 1958), p. 127-161.
    - Information as a measure of the experience of music / David Kraehenbuehl and Edgar Coons., 13 p.; 26 cm. (Box 7, Folder 115)
      Reprinted from The Journal of Aesthetics and Art Criticism, v. 17, no. 4 (June 1959), p. 510-522.
    - Intermediate study: what are the goals? (part I - repertoire) / by David Kraehenbuehl and Richard Chronister., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 115)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, Autumn 1972, p. 18-19.
    - Intermediate study: what are the goals? (part II - technic) / by David Kraehenbuehl., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 115)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, Winter 1973, p. 11-12.
    - Intermediate study: what are the goals?: part III - theory / by David Kraehenbuehl., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 115)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, Autumn 1973, p. 6-7.
    - Is it a "good" piece? [lecture notes], 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 115)
    - Is this piece worth teaching? / by David Kraehenbuehl., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 115)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, Spring 1974, p. 13-14.
    - It's the wrong song / by David Kraehenbuehl., 1 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 115)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, Spring 1977, p. 12.
      Reprinted in Keyboard Arts, Summer 1982, p. 9.
    - Keyboard teachers of harmony [lecture notes], 58 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 116)
    - Learning how to conduct oneself / David Kraehenbuehl., 5 p.; 22 cm. (Box 7, Folder 116)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, August 1981, p. 3-7.
    - Legato: a summary / by David Kraehenbuehl., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 116)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Spring 1986, p. 6-7.
    - Let your fingers do the pedaling / David Kraehenbuehl., 5 p.; 22 cm. (Box 7, Folder 116)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, November 1980, p. 8-12.
    - Music and the machines., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 117)
      Typescript, annotations in ink.
    - Music for teaching: a teacher's need, a composer's responsibility [lecture notes], 7 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 117)
    - Music study [lecture notes], 20 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 117)
    - No sign means something, too / by David Kraehenbuehl., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 117)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Autumn 1985, p. 2-3.
    - On the development of musical systems / David Kraehenbuehl and Christopher Schmidt., 34 p.; 25 cm. (Box 7, Folder 117)
      Annotations in pencil and colored pencil.
      Reprinted from the Journal of Music Theory, 1962, pp. 32-65
    - On the development of musical systems / Christopher U. Light and David Kraehenbuehl., 10 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 117)
    - An ounce of prevention / David Kraehenbuehl., 6 p.; 22 cm. (Box 7, Folder 117)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, October 1981, p. 3-8.
    - Performance analysis: J. S. Bach, Invention no. 8 in F major / by David Kraehenbuehl., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 118)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Spring 1986, p. 8-9.
    - Performance analysis: Johann Sebastian Bach, Little prelude in C minor / by David Kraehenbuehl., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 118)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Winter 1984, p. 12-13.
    - Performance analysis: J. S. Bach, Little prelude no. 1 from "Six little preludes" / by David Kraehenbuehl., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 118)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Spring 1988, p. 10-11.
    - Performance analysis: J. S. Bach, Little prelude no. 8 in F major / by David Kraehenbuehl., 5 p.; 22 cm. (Box 7, Folder 118)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, November 1981, p. 15-19.
    - Performance analysis: J. S. Bach, Prelude and fugue in C minor / by David Kraehenbuehl., 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 118)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Spring 1985, p. 8-10.
    - Performance analysis: Beethoven, Adagio sostenuto from Sonata, opus 27, no. 2 / by David Kraehenbuehl., 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 119)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, Autumn, 1982, p. 10-12.
    - Performance analysis: Ludwig van Beethoven, Für Elise / by David Kraehenbuehl., 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 119)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Autumn 1983, p. 13-15.
    - Performance analysis: Beethoven, Minuet in G / by David Kraehenbuehl., 4 p.; 22 cm. (Box 7, Folder 119)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, January 1982, p. 12-15.
    - Performance analysis: Johannes Brahms, Intermezzo in A minor, op. 76, no. 7 / by David Kraehenbuehl., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 120)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Autumn 1987, p. 4-5.
    - Performance analysis: Johannes Brahms, Waltzes for four hands, opus 39, nos. 1 to 4 / by David Kraehenbuehl., 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 120)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Winter 1989, p. 10-12.
    - Performance analysis: Frederic Chopin, Mazurka, opus 7, no. 1 / by David Kraehenbuehl., 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 121)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Winter 1986, p. 10-12.
    - Performance analysis: Chopin, Nocturne in G minor, op. 37, no. 1 / by David Kraehenbuehl., 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 121)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Winter 1987, p. 4-6.
    - Performance analysis [Frederick Chopin, Prelude in B minor] / David Kraehenbuehl., 4 p.; 22 cm. (Box 7, Folder 121)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, September 1981, p. 7-10.
      Reprinted in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Autumn 1989, p. 12-13.
    - Performance analysis: Frederick Chopin, Prelude in C minor, op. 28, no. 20 / by David Kraehenbuehl., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 121)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Spring 1987, p. 11-12.
    - Performance analysis: Chopin, Prelude in E major, op. 28, no. 9 / by David Kraehenbuehl., 5 p.; 22 cm. (Box 7, Folder 121)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, October 1981, p. 12-16.
    - Performance analysis: Frederick Chopin, Prelude in E minor, opus 28, no. 4 / by David Kraehenbuehl., 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 121)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Spring, 1983, p. 10-12
    - Performance analysis: Muzio Clementi, Sonatina in C major, op. 36, no. 1 / by David Kraehenbuehl., 4 p.; 22 cm. (Box 7, Folder 122)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, December 1981, p. 14-17.
    - Performance analysis: Edvard Grieg, Waltz, opus 12, no. 2 / by David Kraehenbuehl., 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 123)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Autumn 1988, p. 8-10.
    - Performance analysis: Joseph Haydn, Allegro con brio from the Sonata in C major (Hoboken XVI/35) / by David Kraehenbuehl., 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 124)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Autumn 1986, p. 9-11.
    - Performance analysis: Franz Joseph Haydn, Menuet from the Sonata no. 3 in F major, Hoboken XVI/9 / by David Kraehenbuehl., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 124)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Autumn 1985, p. 6-7.
    - Performance analysis: Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart, Allegro from Sonata in G major, K. 283 / by David Kraehenbuehl., 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 125)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Spring 1984, p. 9-11.
    - Performance analysis: Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart, Fantasie in D minor, K.V. 397 / by David Kraehenbuehl., 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 125)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Autumn 1984, p. 2, 10-11.
    - Performance analysis: Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart, Minuet in G major, K. 1 / by David Kraehenbuehl., 4 p.; 22 cm. (Box 7, Folder 125)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, April 1982, p. 7-10.
    - Performance analysis: Franz Schubert, Impromptu in A-flat major, opus 90, no. 4 / by David Kraehenbuehl., 2 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 126)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Winter 1988, p. 12-13.
    - Performance analysis: Franz Schubert, Moment musical in A major, opus 94, no. 6 / by David Kraehenbuehl., 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 126)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Winter 1983, p. 13-15.
    - Performance analysis: Robert Schumann, Träumerei from Kinderszenen, opus 15 / by David Kraehenbuehl., 4 p.; 22 cm. (Box 7, Folder 127)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, February 1982, p. 7-10.
    - Performance analysis: Robert Schumann, Von fremden Ländern und Menschen from Kinderszenen, opus 15 / by David Kraehenbuehl., 3 p.; 22 cm. (Box 7, Folder 127)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, March 1982, p. 15-17.
    - Playing piano or playing music / by David Kraehenbuehl., 3 p.; 28 cm. (Box 7, Folder 128)
      Published in Keyboard Arts Magazine, Winter 1989, p. 13-15.
    - Playing the unmarked slurs / David Kraehenbuehl., 6 p.; 22 cm. (Box 7, Folder 128)
      Published in Keyboard Arts, October 1980, p. 2-7.
    - A Program Note for Advent Tropes., 7 p.; 28. cm. (Box 7, Folder 128)
    - Program notes. The LaSalle Quartet, October 26, 1950. (Box 8, Folder 129)
      Schubert Quartet No. 7 in G minor, Op. posth. -- Piston Quartet No. 1. -- Beethoven Quartet No. 11, Op. 95 in F minor.
    - Program notes. The LaSalle Quartet, February 14, 1951. (Box 8, Folder 129)
      Mozart Quartet in A-major, K. No. 464. -- Wolf Italian Serenade for String Quartet. -- Berg Lyric Suite for String Quartet.
    - Program notes. The New Haven Symphony Orchestra, October 27, 1953. (Box 8, Folder 129)
      Beethoven Coriolanus Overture, Emperor Concerto, Fifth Symphony.
    - Program notes. The New Haven Symphony Orchestra, July 12, 1955. (Box 8, Folder 129)
      Elgar Pomp and Circumstance. -- Liadov Excerpts from Eight Russian Folk Songs. -- Schubert Rosamunde (Entreacte Music No. 2) -- Chabrier Espana.
    - Program notes. The New Haven Symphony Orchestra, July 19, 1955. (Box 8, Folder 129)
      Rodgers The Guadalcanal March from Victory at Sea. -- Rossini Excerpts from The Barber of Seville. -- Gershwin Girl Crazy Overture. -- Songs by Lehar and Herbert. -- Ravel Bolero.
    - Program notes. The New Haven Symphony Orchestra, October 11, 1955. (Box 8, Folder 129)
      Brahms Academic Festival Overture. -- Beethoven Symphony in A Major, No. 7, Opus 92. -- Porter Concerto Concertante for Two Pianos and Orchestra. -- Stravinsky Suite from L'Oiseau de Feu.
    - Program notes. The New Haven Symphony Orchestra, February 21, 1956. (Box 8, Folder 129)
      Bloch Concerto Grosso No. II for Strings. -- Schumann Symphony in B-Flat Major, No. 1, Opus 38. -- Beethoven Concerto for Piano and Orchestra in E-Flat Major, No. 5, Opus 73.
    - Program notes. The New Haven Symphony Orchestra, October 15, 1957. (Box 8, Folder 129)
      Handel Concerto for Organ and Orchestra in B-flat Major. -- Khatchatourian Concerto for Piano and Orchestra. -- Brahms Symphony in E Minor, No. 4, Opus 98.
    - Program notes. The New Haven Symphony Orchestra, April 15, 1958. (Box 8, Folder 129)
      Hérold Zampa Overture. -- Tschaikowsky Concerto for Piano and Orchestra in B-Flat Minor, Opus 23. -- Stravinsky Le Sacre du Printemps.
    - Program notes. The New Haven Symphony Orchestra, October 17-25, 195? (Box 8, Folder 129)
      Gillis January-February-March! -- Beethoven Symphony in A Major, No. 7, Opus 92. -- Saint-Saens Danse Macabre. -- Mendelssohn Concerto for Violin and Orchestra in E Minor, Opus 64. -- Stravinsky Berceuse and Finale from the Firebird Suite.
    - Program notes. The New Haven Symphony Orchestra, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 129)
    - Program notes. The New Haven Symphony Orchestra, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 129)
      Haydn Symphony in D Major (London) -- Hindemith Symphony "Mathis der Maler." -- Mendelssohn Concerto in E-Minor for Violin and Orchestra.
    - Program notes. The New Haven Symphony Orchestra, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 129)
      Mozart Jupiter Symphony, Magic Flute.
    - Program notes. The New Haven S ymphony Orchestra, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 129)
      Smetana Overture to The Bartered Bride. -- Kahn Les Symphonies Bretonnes. -- Sibelius Symphony No. 7. -- Schubert Unfinished Symphony.
    - Program notes. News of the Connecticut Opera Guild, 1957-1958. (Box 8, Folder 129)
      Verdi Aida.